Whether you're shaving for the first time or
want to improve your technique,
we have a few tips for a
softer, more comfortable shave. Shower
beforehand; the warmth and moisture
soften the hair and allow the razor to
glide more easily. This helps protect you from
cuts and irritation.
Use a facial scrub to
remove oils, dirt, and dead skin,
preparing your skin for a comfortable shave. Lather up some shaving gel
and spread it. Gel helps
keep the hair moist, allows the razor to
glide, and
protects you from irritation during shaving.
Check the lube strips; if they
've faded or the blades
feel dull while shaving, use
a new blade.
Make light, gentle strokes. Let
the razor do the work.
The Gillette Fusion Pro Shield has a
pivoting flexball that adapts to the
contours of your face.
Rinse the blades regularly.
Remember never to shave without gel
and never to go over the
same area too often, as
this can lead to irritation.
So, shave with or against the grain.  The
answer is both. Facial hair grows
in many directions, so you'll
shave with and against the grain. Shave
in whichever direction
feels most comfortable. An
advanced multi-blade razor
like this one will give you a comfortable shave,
even against the grain. Use the
precision trimmer on the back to reach
hard-to-reach areas like
under your nose or to
define your sideburns. Wash
your face with cold water and pat it
dry. Apply a nourishing
aftershave to
moisturize and
soothe your skin. Wow, you look great!
For more tips, check out these
videos. Subscribe to our channel so
you'll see when new videos are added,
and tell us
your best shaving tips in the comments.